All right.
Here, Takako.
This is for Azu.
And this one's Hagita's.
What else is in it?
Just a weird picture of a girl, and...
That's mine.
...for some reason, a publicity photo of Messi.
There's also a picture of
all of us, and Kakeru's letter.
My recently-turned 26-year-old self
is filled with regrets.
She said it'll start at ten.
Right, right. So I think that'll leave
some free time in the afternoon.
I'll leave it to you, then.
Naho!
From myself?
Are you okay on time?
Oh, no!
Goodness...
She's not gonna make it.
Today's diary entry decided.
"April 6th: The first time in my life I overslept."
Second-years stay in the same class,
so this spring might not feel like a new start.
Still, let's give it our all this year.
Glad to be with you all again.
Today we have the opening ceremony,
and then I'll distribute your textbooks.
Let's see... Also, there's someone
I'd like to introduce to you all today.
A transfer student?
Is it a girl?
Score!
Wait quietly for a bit, kids.
Ten years in the future?
How did it know?
A transfer student...
All right, settle down, everyone!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
And his name is...
This is Naruse Kakeru-kun.
Naruse-kun's come all the way from Tokyo, you see.
This is his first time living in Nagano,
so be nice to him, everyone.
Go on, Naruse. Say a few words.
It's nice to meet you all.
Okay, you can sit next to Takamiya.
Over there. The seat all the way at the back.
Good morning.
I am the principal, Sugiyama.
This April, against the backdrop
of the blossoming cherry trees,
our school embarks on yet another new year
with a fresh, new class of students.
Naho, let's go home.
Oh, sure.
Hey! Come have our bread for lunch!
Really? Yay!
Thanks.
Hey, transfer student!
Kakeru-kun, right?
Walk home with us!
I've... kind of got...
Kind of got nothing!
Let's get to know each other!
Sorry to spring this on you.
Hey, Kakeru-kun. Come eat our bread, too.
Her family runs a bakery.
It's good stuff.
Um...
Come walk home with us.
Don't let this half-day go to waste.
Isn't this...
Tokyo, huh?
We'll show you around Matsumoto!
Yeah! How 'bout it?
How 'bout it?
Okay... Just let me send one email first.
Okay!
Sure.
Awesome!
I'll go on ahead to swipe some bread for us!
I'm expecting a lot! Like a truckload!
Thanks.
Mustard-greens bun.
Man, I'm totally craving bread right now!
I'm really hungry.
I wonder why I shouldn't invite him...
Hey, Naho!
So, intros.
This guy's Hagita. Hagita Saku.
This is Naho. Takamiya Naho.
And that there's Chino Takako.
Nice to meet you.
And I'm Suwa Hiroto.
Call me Suwa.
Got it.
Hey! Wait!
Come on, Azu! I'm starving!
Sorry! It'll finish baking soon.
I'll have to get it later.
And little miss baker is Murasaka Azusa.
Call me Azu.
Azusa...
Oh, did you notice?
Kakeru-kun, which train
did you ride here from Tokyo?
The Azusa limited express.
I knew it! That's hilarious!
Kakeru-kun, do you know the song
"Azusa 2" by The Hunters?
Oh, so that's why?
Exactly! That's why my nickname
in middle school was...
"The Hunter"!
Not "Azusa 2"?
Later, it changed to "Huntsman."
And yours was "Crooked Glasses,"
because they were always
crooked to the right!
Oh, shut up.
Take off at 8:00 sharp on the Azusa.
But the Azusa 2 doesn't leave at 8:00 sharp.
To Shinjuku?
Somewhere further.
I don't have the money for that.
Just go.
The other night, my dad
sang "Azusa 2" at karaoke.
Where?!
Mount Yari. Carry a deer back.
The music video played.
Not happening. I can't carry a deer.
What, really? I wanna see it.
You guys are really running
with the "hunter" thing...
You're making it awkward for Kakeru-kun. See?
He's laughing!
He's laughing...
What was the funniest part?
"Huntsman."
All of things?!
Look at that.
I'm glad we invited him.
Sorry for the wait! I got the goods!
Behold!
We've got cutlet buns, pork miso buns, curry buns,
mustard-greens buns, melon buns,
and apple cinnamon rolls here.
Today I've got two of each, all freshly baked.
My dad's bread is the best in the world!
It's unrivaled!
Which do you want, Kakeru-kun?
Anything's fine with me,
though I am curious about
the mustard-greens bun.
It's great. Try it.
Dibs on the other mustard-greens bun!
In your dreams! This one's mine!
Give it back, Hagita!
I'll have an apple cinnamon roll.
I'll take a curry bun.
Huh?
And your other one?
Cutlet bun.
Sure.
I love the curry buns from Azu's family's bakery.
How about you, Naho? What do you want?
Hey, Hagita, that's my curry bun.
You can eat them anytime you want!
I don't want you to have it.
I'm fine with anything.
Give it.
Really? No need to hold back, you know.
Really, really.
Okay, since you like sweet stuff,
you get a melon bun and an apple cinnamon roll.
Thanks.
Not enough for you, Suwa?
I wouldn't mind another three or four.
Come buy more later, then.
Curry bun.
I'll trade you for the melon bun.
S-Sure.
Don't tell me he figured it out?
Was it that obvious I wanted the curry bun?
See you tomorrow.
Bring more curry buns next time.
Kakeru-kun, did you like the bread?
Oh... Yeah, I did.
Later, everyone.
Later! Bye-bye!
Later.
Oh, Kakeru-kun.
Is it okay if we just call you "Kakeru"?
Sure. I prefer that.
Oh right, the letter.
They say the same thing.
Even the handwriting's the same.
What, why?
My sister came up with it.
Something about seeing
something on the cat's butt.
Seriously?
Yeah, no problem.
Kakeru-kun is absent?
I dunno.
I forgot to ask for his number.
I wonder what's up.
What, curious?
Huh? N-No...
Kakeru-kun didn't come to school for some time.
In other words, this is a new number
that results from the square root of -1.
My goal is to make childhood dreams come true.
The letter...
My goal...
That day...
I didn't do as the letter said.
I wonder if it has anything to do
with why Kakeru-kun is absent.
Maybe this letter explains why Kakeru-kun
hasn't been coming to school.
In the Azumi Basin, flowers bloom into apples.
The mist rolls in, and wets the hair.
The girl from Shinano has wet hair.
Kakeru-kun—er, I mean, Kakeru!
Hey!
Yo, Kakeru!
How're you feeling?
Where have you been for the past two weeks?
Ditching.
Oh?
That's not what's going on here.
You think this is the west?
We won!
Easy win! Easy win!
Our team's in good hands with Naho in it.
You pitch like nobody else.
I can tell you were on the softball team.
That was just in middle school.
I bet you're tired after pitching so much.
Nah.
Time to clean up.
We'll take care of it, so just relax.
We've got this. We're gonna win.
Nagasaka!
Pass to Nakayama!
It's Suwa and the others.
Oh, Kakeru-kun... I mean, Kakeru!
Which event did you sign up for?
I'm not playing anything.
What? Why?
I haven't been to class at all.
You didn't have to worry about that.
What'd you pick?
Softball.
Does it hurt?
Oh, yeah.
My shoes are too small.
Too small?
For some reason, they got my
size wrong when I ordered them.
You didn't exchange them?
I missed my chance to bring it up.
So Suwa plays soccer, huh?
Stay on your marks!
Here, Hagita.
Huh, me?
Jeez... Hagita-kun sucks.
Naho!
We're starting!
Okay! Well, I'm off.
Sure.
Man, I haven't eaten anything today!
Liar.
What? They changed their pitcher?
She's on the softball team!
Now?
Strike! Batter out!
No fair, putting a pitcher
like that in for the final match.
I'll never get a hit.
What's with that pitcher?
Amazing.
It'll be a piece of cake!
Or maybe not.
Time out!
Oh, yeah...
Naho! Pinch hit for us?
This is the last thing we'll ever ask of you!
It's really happening!
But...
If you slam us one, our victory is assured!
You were on the softball team. You can hit it.
Please!
Two outs, bases loaded.
If I get a hit, we'll win.
But if I get called out, we'll lose.
I can't do this.
I-I'm sorry. I don't think
I can get a hit off her, either.
What? Please!
Don't force her.
Her foot is hurt.
What? Hurt? Naho, is that true?
What happened?
No, it isn't an injury.
And besides, it's my own fault.
Then I'll take a crack at it!
Just forgive me if I strike out, okay?
Is it okay to say no?
The reason I regret refusing must be because
I forced the responsibility onto my friend,
and didn't do something I knew I could do.
A-Actually, I'll do it!
Naho?
The pain in my foot will fade eventually.
But the regret won't.
Not even in ten years.
The me of the present doesn't want
to live the next ten years regretting this!
The second pitch will be...
inside...
and low.
Hot damn, Naho!
Naho, you gotta run!
You haven't crossed home yet!
Oh!
MVP!
We did it! We did it! Go! Go! Run the bases!
Our class won at softball.
And our soccer team apparently
had a brilliant win too, thanks to Suwa.
Ambulance here.
Show me your foot.
That's okay.
Take a seat over there.
You've got a blister. I'm going to disinfect it.
Ow!
You need to tell them they got the wrong size.
Yeah...
But it's only for P.E., so it's not really a problem.
It's too late now, anyway.
I'll just endure it.
Endure too much, and it'll be your loss.
I prefer it if it's just my loss.
As long as I'm not a bother to others.
Nobody can tell, so if I just endure it,
there's no problem, right?
That's how I've always handled things.
I know. I've seen.
There, all done. Take care.
Thank you.
No problem.
You too, Kakeru!
If you want to play soccer, you have to say so!
I've been...
watching you, too, Kakeru!
Your home run...
was pretty cool.
Next year, I'll be sure to play soccer.
I'm better than Suwa, so be sure to watch.
I will. I promise.
Everything written in that letter really does happen.
To the me ten years in the future,
do you have one less regret now?
Naho!
Look at these flowers. Beautiful, right?
What's that bouquet for?
It's for Kakeru.
He doesn't care about stuff like that.
It's fine.
To the me of the past, ten years ago.
You've got a lot of happiness and joy ahead of you.
I hope you can sense that happiness.
I hope you don't let it slip away from you.
I wrote this letter because
I don't want you, my 16-year-old self,
to have regrets you'll carry
with you for the rest of your life.